Guide to the Theodore Dorie Friend Collection, 1897-1990
Friend, Theodore Dorie Collection
- Series III: The Blue Eyed Enemy
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, The sources (2 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy Carbon copy (1 of 3), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy Carbon copy (2 of 3), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy Carbon copy (3 of 3), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Authors revisions July 1987 (1 of 3), 1987 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Xerox copy of authors revisions of copy- edited ms., returned to Princeton University Press, July 87
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Authors revisions July 1987 (2 of 3), 1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Authors revisions July 1987 (3 of 3), 1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Authors Revisions Dec. 1987 (1 of 3), 1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Xerox copy of authors revisions of master page proof, and of index, sent to P.U.P., 22 Dec 87
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Authors Revisions Dec. 1987 (2 of 3), 1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Authors Revisions Dec. 1987 (3 of 3), 1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy; Unbound copy, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Alfonso Felix, Blue-Eyed Enemy Correspondence, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous research notecards and materials, 1967-1971 (Box 24)
- Series IV: Research Materials, Philippines and Indonesia
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (1 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    O.W. Wolters, Southeast Asia to 1400 (1966-67)-Course notes
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (2 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    O.W. Wolters, Southeast Asia to 1400 (1966-67)
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (3 of 13), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    SE Asia Since 1400, Cornell University, 1967: OW Wolters-Course notes
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (4 of 13), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    SE Asia Since 1400, Cornell University, 1967: OW Wolters
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (5 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    de la Costa, Corpuz
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (6 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Majority-Minorities in Burma (Lehman vs Leach)
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (7 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Insular-Peninsular History of SEA 1400-1800
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (8 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Approaching SE Asian history, philosophical, moral, and tactical problems
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (9 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Portuguese Power: Trade and Empire, 16th C Asia; Controversies Concerning Portuguese Trade and Empire in 16th C Asia
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (10 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Cambodia 1701-04
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (11 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Indonesian Society and its Political Cultures
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (12 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    SEA Since 1400- Tutorial and Reading Notes (2nd Sem. 1966-67)
  - History 495 Lecture and Reading Notes (13 of 13), 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    SE Asia to 1400 Notes on Reading, Cornell 1966-67
  - Soeroto, Sedjaial Proklamasi 17 Agustus 1945, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Text and correspondence
  - Translated Articles from Dutch on Indonesia, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    New Order and Kudeta; Framed Malaysia currency
  - Japanese Military Administration in Indonesia, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Dept of Commerce Publication
  - RVO Materials on Japanese in Indonesia in WWII, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Feudalism in Japan and Indonesia, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Book by Peter Duus, correspondence with Paul Wheatley
  - Philippines, Assistance and Resistance to Japanese, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Notes and excerpts
  - Memoir of B.C. de Jonge, translation (1 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Text
  - Memoir of B.C. de Jonge, translation (2 of 2), 1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Philippines Excerpts and Drafts, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    Penders, Sturtevant, Stanley, Steinberg, Luthy, Landes, Owen (Compadre Colonialism)
  - Larawan 1972-1973- Philippine Embassy Newsletter, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Ferdinand Marcos, Martial Law 1971-1973, 1971-1973 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Press and Newspapers
  - Dutch to English Translations (1 of 2), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Correspondence, business
  - Dutch to English Translations (2 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Chairil Anwar
  - Njonja S. Pudjo Semadi and Suedjono, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Correspondence regarding Djojobojo Prophecy
  - Indonesian Independence and Djawa Baroe Research Index, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Translation/notes on preparations for independence; notes on research index
  - US Study on Japanese Military Psychology, 1944-1945, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Translations of Japanese WWII Materials (1 of 7), 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Memoirs and correspondence
  - Translations of Japanese WWII Materials (2 of 7), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Saka Kuniyasu, The Battle of the Philippines and the War Trials
  - Translations of Japanese WWII Materials (3 of 7), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, Murata- Mukoyawa trans.
  - Translations of Japanese WWII Materials (4 of 7), 1968 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Oshima Kazako, Murata Memoir-Manila and Sugamo Diaries
  - Translations of Japanese WWII Materials (5 of 7), 1970 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Mukoyama, Defense Agency Study of Philippines
  - Translations of Japanese WWII Materials (6 of 7), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Iwamura, Taniguchi; Defense Agency
  - Translations of Japanese WWII Materials (7 of 7), 1968 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Oshima, Kazuko; Miyoshi Memoir; Countermeasures against local people
  - Photographs, Japanese National Archive, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    4 large photographs and Friend book jacket
  - Nihon Kenpei Sheishi, Philippines sections, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Translations of Japanese WWII Materials (1 of 2), 1986 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Translations of Japanese WWII Materials (2 of 2), 1986 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Chuo Koron essay, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Authority and Democracy in the Philippines
  - International Association of Historians, October 1986, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Stanley Karnow Philippines television program, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Torkunov translation of Russian chapter, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Sternglass research, National Archives, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Sternglass research, Library of Congress, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Guy Hobbs: Bibliography and Checking, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Takahashi: “A New Era of Japan-Philippine Relations”, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Willem Wolters: Taxation Systems in Philippines and Indonesia 19th C., 1981 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Summary, research materials on Japanese occupation of Indonesia, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - P. Van’t Veer, De Atjeh-oorlog; Abstract, 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - A Preliminary Analysis of the October 1, 1965 Coup in Indonesia, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Research note, confidential bulletin and publications
  - Indonesia News and Views by Soedjatmoko, 1967, 1969, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    Dyason memorial lectures 1967; Indonesia news and views by Soedjatmoko 1969, 1970
  - The Development of Chinese Studies, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    History: Western imperialism and Chinese expansion, 1870-1970
  - Governor General Report, Philippines, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Xerox copy of selected parts and associated BIA files
  - Japanese Record of the Indonesian Independence Movement, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - “Skandal Sex Sukarno”, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Research Notes and Materials, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - WWII in Philippines, Materials, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Laurel Library, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Correspondence with Capitulo, Laurel and research note, America’s stewardship in the Philippines
  - Political and Economic Development in the Philippines, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Agency for International Development Report
  - Jose P. Laurel, Trial for Treason, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Transcripts
  - Presidential calendar, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    photocopy
  - Papers, Japan and the Philippines, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    “The Development of Japanese Studies in Southeast Asia”, “Japan and the Philippine Revolution”, “A Tapir in Prison”
  - Area Handbook on the Philippines (1 of 2), 1955 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Area Handbook on the Philippines (2 of 2), 1955 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Sukarno GSK newspaper clippings, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript, “Two Javanese, Two traditions”, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Dissertation chapter by unknown
  - Demographics and Statistical Information, Dutch East Indies, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Dutch East Indies Research, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Bureau of Insular Affairs, Documents and Provisions (1 of 3), 1898-1930s (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Bureau of Insular Affairs, Documents and Provisions (2 of 3), 1930s (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Bureau of Insular Affairs, Documents and Provisions (3 of 3), 1930s (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Leila Pool Collection (1 of 3), 1898-1930s (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Important documents on American colonial administration of the Philippines, photos
  - Leila Pool Collection (2 of 3), 1898-1930s (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Important documents on American colonial administration of the Philippines
  - Leila Pool Collection (3 of 3), 1898-1930s (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings (1 of 2), 1958-1965 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings (2 of 2), 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - The World in 2030 A.D. and Guerrilla Resistance Movement in Philippines, 1945-1948 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - An Analysis of the Philippines Economic Crisis, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Statements to US House of Representatives concerning the Philippines, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, Southeast Asia and Philippines, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Statistics and Development Analyses in Philippines, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Direct investment Statistics, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Indonesian Nationalism Manuscript (1 of 2), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Indonesian Nationalism Manuscript (2 of 2), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Cornell Microfilms Checklist, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Newspapers on Marcos Protest, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings on Phillipines (1 of 7), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Ninoy Aquino Assassination
  - Newspaper Clippings on Phillipines (2 of 7), 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Aquino, Ninoy campaigns
  - Newspaper Clippings on Phillipines (3 of 7), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    Ferdinand Marcos, Military Bases, and Aquino Investigation
  - Newspaper Clippings on Phillipines (4 of 7), 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Secretary Open Forum and Marcos Crisis
  - Newspaper Clippings on Phillipines (5 of 7), 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Extra judicial Killings, Indonesia and Philippines
  - Newspaper Clippings on Phillipines (6 of 7), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Ferdinand Marcos and 1984 National Assembly Elections
  - Newspaper Clippings on Phillipines (7 of 7), 1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    The Philippines: the Election and the Situation
  - The Cellar Bookshop- Notices and receipts, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Assessing America’s Options with the Philippines, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Woodrow Wilson International Center dialogue, newspapers, articles, strategic map
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1984-1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Country Studies Bulletins and Newsletters, Senate Philippines Staff Report
  - International Finance System, Articles and Chapters, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - USA v Marcos, et al. and Asia Society, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Marcos War Record, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Reform in the Philippines and US Relationship, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Research and Writing Publications, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Notes Between Two Empires and Blue Eyed Enemy, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Series V: Other Publications and papers
  - Lords and Bondsman: The Philippines, Indonesia, and Japanese Impact, 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Manuscript, responses and notes from other scholars
  - The Yale Review- Friend review essay “An Eye for Infinity”, 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Crisis in the Philippines, “Philippine-American Tensions in History” (1 of 4), 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Crisis in the Philippines, “Philippine-American Tensions in History” (2 of 4), 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Crisis in the Philippines, “Philippine-American Tensions in History” (3 of 4), 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Crisis in the Philippines, “Philippine-American Tensions in History” (4 of 4), 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Philippine Studies, “Yellow Revolution” (1 of 3), 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Philippine Studies, “Yellow Revolution” (2 of 3), 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Philippine Studies, “Yellow Revolution” (3 of 3), 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - The Kenpeitai in Java and Sumatra (1 of 3), 1986 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    Shimer/Hobbs Translation
  - The Kenpeitai in Java and Sumatra (2 of 3), 1986 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - The Kenpeitai in Java and Sumatra (3 of 3), 1986 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - The Authoritative History of the Kenpeitai, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    Selections
  - The Kenpeitai in Java and Sumatra, Preparation for Publication, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Kenpeitai in Philippines, Shimer/Hobbs Translation, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Kenpeitai in Java, History, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Statements, Kenpeitai in Siam and Dutch East Indies, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Travel documents, Seminars and Lectures in Philippines, China
  - Seminars and Lectures in Philippines (1 of 2), 1980 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    Preparatory Material-For trip to Philippines in 1980; Book chapters, research notes, correspondence with Swarthmore
  - Seminars and Lectures in Philippines (2 of 2), 1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - American Higher Ed in 2001, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Outline notes for presentations in Manila, 7-16-80- USICA: Trip logistics; Philippines, 1980: Laurel, Lopez, FAPE materials; Correspondence with Ben, Charlie and Larry, Dore, Ellen, presentations, research note, report, logistics,
  - Reading Materials, American Assembly at Philadelphia, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Trip to China, August 10-24, 1977, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Magazine, logistics, Chinese Language notes and guidance.
  - China, Reference Materials, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Swarthmore Briefing packet, People’s Republic of China, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Friend Trip to Jakarta with USIS, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Friend Travel Reimbursement Records, 1975-1981 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Wilson Fellow Research Business- Correspondence and records, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Series VII: Conferences and Papers
  - Association of Asian Studies- Papers, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - International Association of Historians of Asia (1 of 2), 1983 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Conference information, Friend’s paper, Anthony Reid letter day of Aquino assassination
  - International Association of Historians of Asia (2 of 2), 1983 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Papers
  - “American Foreign Policy: Varieties of Morality”, Speech, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Notes, speech, and research sources
  - Department of State Conference on the Philippines- Papers, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Conference on Indonesia, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Papers, correspondence, Far Eastern Economic Review articles
  - AAS Princeton Philippines Panel, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Re-Inventing Europe- Papers, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Global Dilemmas: The World of the 1980s- Conference Papers, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - “Southeast Asian Studies: Options for the Future,” papers, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    Wilson Center East Asia Program Conference
  - NIRA Conference Papers, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    "Japanese and American Responses to an Unknown Future"
  - International Association of Historians of Asia- Papers, notes, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Conference: A New Road for the Philippines, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - FPRI conference 87, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Friendly Tyrants Conference, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Notes, Correspondence, Articles
  - Friendly Tyrants Conference (1 of 2)- Papers, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Friendly Tyrants Conference (2 of 2)- Papers, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Friendly Tyrants, Papers (1 of 3), 1987 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Friendly Tyrants, Papers (2 of 3), 1987 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Friendly Tyrants, Papers (3 of 3), 1987 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Friendly Tyrants ORBIS Issue, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Ferdinand Marcos Response and Friend Rejoinder
  - Friendly Tyrants Publication Proofs, 1988-1990 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Series VIII: The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection
  - Olin Library Scans, Indonesia (1 of 3), 1977 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Olin Library Scans, Indonesia (2 of 3), 1977 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Olin Library Scans, Indonesia (3 of 3), 1977 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Sukarno’s Wartime Rhetoric and its Aims (1942-1945) (1 of 3), 1983 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Sukarno’s Wartime Rhetoric and its Aims (1942-1945) (2 of 3), 1983 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Sukarno’s Wartime Rhetoric and its Aims (1942-1945) (3 of 3), 1983 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Asia-Raya Newspaper Articles, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Philippines Communist Party Sources, 1933, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Philippines Politics and Economy Sources, 1933-1934, 1933-1934 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 10 – 17, 1910 – 1917 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 1910 – 1914, 1910 – 1914 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 18 – 19, 1918 – 1919 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 18 – 22, 1918 – 1922 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 21 – 22, 1921 – 1922 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 23 – 24- The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 27 – 29, 1923 – 1922 1927 – 1929 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 31 (1 of 2), 1931 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 31 (2 of 2), 1931 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 32, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 31-32, 1931 – 1932 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 32-33, 1932 – 1933 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 33 (1 of 3), 1933 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 33 (2 of 3), 1933 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 33 (3 of 3), 1933 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 33 – 34, 1933 – 1934 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 34, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 34 – 41, 1934 – 1941 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 37 – 39, 1937 – 1941 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 35 – 40- Copy of typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 1936 – 1939, 1935 – 1940 1936 – 1939 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Copy of typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 1936, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Copy of typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 1936 – 37, 1936 – 1937 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Copy of typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 1937, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Copy of typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 1937 – 1938, 1937 – 1938 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Copy of typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection 1939, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. I, 1935-1939 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. II; part I (1 of 3), 1935-1939 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. II; part I (2 of 3), 1935-1939 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. II; part I (3 of 3), 1935-1939 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. III; part I (1 of 3), 1935-1939 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. III; part I (2 of 3), 1935-1939 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. III; part I (3 of 3), 1935-1939 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. IV (1 of 5), 1935-1939 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. IV (2 of 5), 1935-1939 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. IV (3 of 5), 1935-1939 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. IV (4 of 5), 1935-1939 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. IV (5 of 5), 1935-1939 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. V (1 of 3), 1935-1939 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. V (2 of 3), 1935-1939 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Selected typescript the President Manuel L. Quezon Collection Vol. V (3 of 3), 1935-1939 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Series IX: Personal documents: Swarthmore College, applications, Wilson Fellowship
  - Swarthmore College, Benefits, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Swarthmore College, Salary and Household reimbursement, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Swarthmore College, Activities of Elizabeth Friend, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Application materials, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Institute for Advanced Study Fellowship asnd Huntington Library
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center Fellows, 1983 – 1984 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Papers, biographies, newspaper articles
  - Woodrow Wilson Fellowship Business, 1982 – 1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Application, correspondence, records
- Series X: Microforms, Disks, transparencies
  - National Archives Slides on the Philippines, 1898-1955, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - List of Rob and Pringle Transparencies, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Microfilm- Japan, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1868-1945; Anti-Japanese Movement in the Phils, Sect 1: 1928-36, Sect 2: 1936-41; Reel 459 (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- Japan, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1868-1945; “Land Problems in Darao,” Jan’26- Dec ’41; Reel 460 (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- Japan, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1868-1945; “Land Problems in Darao,” Jan’26- Dec ’41; Reel 461 (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- Japan, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1868-1945; Japanese C of C PI and UD66 re rec of indep. ’43; Reel 275 (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- Japan, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1868-1945; Misc documents relating to internal political conditions in various countries: the Philippine Islands, Oct 1943-Aug 1944; Reel 5707 (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- Japan-Philippines Wartime, May-Oct ‘43 (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- Philippine Handbooks, Selected Portions, vols I-IV, 1962 (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- National Archives, World War Records Division (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- Rejksinstituut voor Oorlogs documentation; Interregations and Statesments of Japanese presence, NEI and Singapore, 1945-46; captured documents of Japanese Administration, etc. (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- Japanese Army and Navy; Intelligence Reports, 1933, including on US and Philippines (Box 19)
  - Microfilm- Japanese Army and Navy, Gen Rep and Mil Govt 6-30-42; Heads of Mil Govt and Meet 11-30-42 (Box 19)